(Diverted from Fang and Da group)
（转自方达组）
(Is a street terrorist group.)
（是街头恐怖组织。）
(Gang Fang specializes in fraud)
（方刚专攻诈骗）
(and blackmail.)
（和勒索。）
(Redirected from Gang Da)
（重定向自刚达）
(collect debt,)
（追债，）
(kidnapper)
（绑匪）
(And run a casino in secret.)
（并秘密经营一家赌场。）
(They are the first resort)
（他们是第一个度假村）
When the heirs investigate a case.
当继承人 调查案件时。
(No one knows the things that cannot be expressed)
（无法表达的事情没有人知道）
(They're better than they do.)
（他们比他们做的更好。）
(Diverted from 5 villages)
（从5个村庄改道）
(Name a nickname)
（起个昵称）
(Two mice and three wolves)
（两只老鼠和三只狼）
(Bath)
（洗澡）
(But)
（但）
(They refer to themselves as)
（他们称自己为）
(Five Malays)
（五位马来人）
Their relationship needs support from officials.
他们的关系需要 官方的支持。
(Redirected from Du County)
（转自杜县）
(I am a teacher.)
（我是老师。）
Come on.
快点。
Happy
快乐的
== City == = Episode 2=
==城市==== 第2集=
You ran with me on purpose.
你是故意跟我跑的。
That's not me.
不是我。
You are the one who ran to me.
你就是那个跑到我身边的人。
You blame me?
你怪我吗？
Do you know how much?
你知道多少钱吗？
This wine is 20 years old.
此酒已有20年历史。
It is a gift prepared by my master.
这是师父给我准备的礼物。
I'm so sorry.
我很抱歉。
Sorry?
对不起？
Do you think an apology is enough?
你觉得道歉就够了吗？
You...
你...
This is blackmail.
这是敲诈勒索。
Blackmail?
勒索？
Go to Yemen
去也门
And see if they will blackmail you.
看看他们是否会敲诈你。
Are there any witnesses?
是否有任何证人？
We are witnesses.
我们是见证人。
I see.
我懂了。
This guy didn't watch his step.
这家伙没有注意自己的脚步。
He ran to you.
他跑向你。
and broke the jar.
并打破了罐子。
Bro,
兄弟，
This wine is definitely worth a lot, isn't it?
这酒绝对值很多钱，不是吗？
I just bought it from Tianxing Shop for five silver taels.
刚从天行店花了 五两银子买的。
No need to explain. Let's go to Yemen.
无需解释。 我们去也门吧。
We obey the law.
我们遵守法律。
Cut it off. Go.
截断。去。
Tuan,
团,
I blame the wine money.
怪罪酒钱。
This...
这...
No, this money is not enough.
不，这些钱还不够。
Let's go to Yemen
我们去也门吧
to obtain judgment.
以获得判断力。
Go away.
离开。
Don't.
不。
Gentlemen.
先生们。
Hello, sir.
你好先生。
Who are you?
你是谁？
I'm just a pedestrian.
我只是一个行人。
I feel sorry for this old man,
心疼这个老人
So I want to help him.
所以我想帮助他。
To pay for it?
要付钱吗？
Of.
的。
Tuan,
团,
You are so kind.
你真好。
No need for this.
不需要这个。
How much?
多少？
To be honest,
说实话，
that's four taels and six fen,
就是四两六分，
More than 10 shillings.
10多先令。
Tuan,
团,
please help me
请帮我
and let him go.
并让他走。
Okay.
好的。
After all, I am kind.
毕竟我是善良的。
The rest I will redeem myself.
剩下的我自己来救赎。
Old man,
老头子，
You have met a good person.
你遇到了一个好人。
Remember to pay the money back.
记得把钱还回来。
Of.
的。
Sir, I will definitely refund this money.
先生，这笔钱我一定会退还的。
To calm you down,
为了让你平静下来，
Let's write proof of debt.
我们来写一下债务证明吧。
can you read
你会读...吗
I can't read.
我无法阅读。
But that's okay. You just write it down.
但没关系。你只需写下来。
I'll put my thumbs up.
我会竖起大拇指。
I am poor,
我穷，
I have never owed money to anyone.
我从来没有欠过任何人钱。
If yes,
如果是，
I will write one.
我会写一篇。
Tiger Scorpion.
虎蝎.
Sangeng.
Sangeng.
I've been watching you for a while.
我已经观察你有一段时间了。
Same old trick again.
又是老把戏了。
What do you mean?
你是什​​么意思？
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
How about drinking tea?
喝茶怎么样？
No rush.
不着急。
Liu Lao'er, kan?
Liu Lao'er, kan?
Yes sir.
是的先生。
I am Liu Lao'er.
我是刘老二。
Who else is in your family?
你家里还有谁？
My wife died early.
我的妻子去世得很早。
His son and wife died of smallpox.
他的儿子和妻子死于 天花。
Only my grandson I was left in the family.
家里只剩下我的孙子了。
You are a lonely old man. I think so much.
你是一个孤独的老人。 我想了这么多。
What do you mean by this, sir?
先生，您这话是什么意思？
What property do you own?
您拥有什么财产？
What can a poor family have?
一个贫穷的家庭能拥有什么？
Only three thatched rooms,
只有三间茅草房，
Lotus Field,
莲花田，
and paddy fields.
和稻田。
How old is the boy?
男孩几岁了？
He is only 13 years old.
他只有13岁。
Liu Lao'er,
Liu Lao'er,
These people must have
这些人必须有
their eyes for a while.
他们的眼睛看了一会儿。
Do not move.
不要动。
Who are you?
你是谁？
You look weird.
你看起来很奇怪。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
He's new here.
他是新来的。
Come on now.
现在来吧。
And give honor to Him.
并将荣耀归给他。
Sangeng.
Sangeng.
Liu Lao'er,
Liu Lao'er,
If you sign Proofs of debt with him,
如果你 和他签署债务证明，
Interest will be calculated daily.
利息将按日计算。
As a component of interest,
作为兴趣的组成部分，
In less than a month, your home
不到一个月，你的家
Lotus Pond and Paddy Field Then everything will be his.
荷塘和稻田， 那么一切都是他的了。
and this is not the end.
这还没有结束。
What is most valuable to them
什么对他们来说最有价值
is your grandson.
是你的孙子。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I will ruin your business.
我会毁了你的生意。
My lord specifically told you
主人特意告诉你
Not intended for children.
不适合儿童。
Captain Leng...
冷队长……
He made the rules,
他制定了规则，
But he is dead.
但他已经死了。
So you think
所以你认为
Are the rules gone now?
现在规则都消失了吗？
I heard that Captain Leng
听说冷队长
many rules for you.
许多规则适合你。
You have to have your own rules, right?
你必须有自己的规则，对吗？
I...
我...
I don't care about that.
我不在乎这个。
There aren't many rules.
没有太多规则。
But since I
但自从我
take over his post,
接替他的职务，
I will trouble you in the future.
我以后会麻烦你的。
I hope
我希望
When the time comes,
在时机成熟时，
You'll help me, okay?
你会帮助我，好吗？
Captain Yi,
Captain Yi,
I only have one thing to say.
我只有一件事要说。
What's that?
那是什么？
We show our respect,
我们表达我们的敬意，
And you complement each other.
而且你们是互补的。
Then,
然后，
I will reply a lot
我会回复很多
If you show
如果你显示
quite respectful.
相当恭敬。
Well done, Captain Yi.
干得好，易队长。
You are good too.
你也很好。
Happy
快乐的
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
Did you come specifically? Do you want to do business again today?
你是专门来的吗？ 今天你还想做生意吗？
It's just a coincidence.
这只是一个巧合。
I came to see your master.
我是来看你师父的。
He is not here.
他不在这儿。
More?
更多的？
I have been here several times.
我来过这里好几次了。
Okay. How about this?
好的。这个怎么样？
Tell me in Yemen
告诉我在也门
when your master returns.
当你的主人回来的时候。
You need to tell your master clearly
你要跟你的主人说清楚
Wait for me here.
在这里等我。
This task is yours now.
这个任务现在是你的了。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
You make it difficult for me.
你让我很为难。
How can it cause you problems?
它怎么会给你带来问题呢？
Isn't that what you're all about traveling every day?
这不就是你 每天旅行的目的吗？
No.
不。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
Five people are five people.
五个人就是五个人。
You don't have to just come to us, do you?
你不必非得来找我们，是吗？
My lord should not
我的主不应该
The only one you don't see.
唯一一个你看不到的。
So you're all involved.
所以你们都参与其中。
You gentlemen all pretend to be gone.
你们先生们都假装消失了。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
A few things
一些东西
better
更好的
leave unstated.
不加说明。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
Anything else?
还要别的吗？
Send me a message, okay?
给我留言好吗？
Okey.
好的。
Go away.
离开。
Yesterday we caught a prostitute.
昨天我们抓到一个妓女。
He must be over 60 years of age,
他应该已经60多岁了
However, he still has customers.
然而，他仍然有客户。
Tell your master to take it from Yemen.
告诉你的主人 从也门拿走它。
Whore?
妓女？
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
We do not do business with prostitutes.
我们不与妓女做生意。
The old whore said
老妓女说
Your master is his son.
你的主人是他的儿子。
(Bath)
（洗澡）
Captain Yi,
Captain Yi,
Do gangsters usually gather in these bathrooms?
歹徒通常会聚集 在这些浴室里吗？
That's their rule.
这是他们的规则。
Everyone is naked,
每个人都赤身裸体，
No one can hide a knife.
没有人能隐藏一把刀。
Very hot.
很热。
It's September but it's still hot.
虽然已经九月了，但天气还是很热。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Two mice and three wolves
两只老鼠和三只狼
Did you really turn to Captain Yi?
你真的去找易队长了吗？
Shicong, do you know
世聪你知道吗
gangsters in our area Are the poorest in the country?
我们地区的黑帮 是全国最穷的吗？
Is it true?
这是真的吗？
Our country is the richest.
我们国家是最富有的。
All because of my master.
这一切都是因为我的师父。
He has prescribed three prohibitions for them.
他为他们规定了三项禁令。
Do they follow the rules?
他们遵守规则吗？
that much?
那么多？
What is wrong?
怎么了？
Nothing. Go home.
没有什么。回家。
Mother
母亲
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
You're back.
你回来了。
mother,
母亲，
Lantern is out.
灯笼出来了。
Come in.
进来。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
Your master is dead.
你的主人死了。
You may have to step down as a bailiff.
您可能必须 辞去法警职务。
mother,
母亲，
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
You are not suitable for the job.
你不适合这份工作。
mother,
母亲，
There are good officers.
有好官。
Is your master a good person?
你的主人是个好人吗？
Tuan,
团,
It's finished.
都结束了。
Mr. Cui gave ten taels.
崔先生给了十两。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
when I asked you for money before,
之前我向你要钱的时候
You always try everything
你总是尝试一切
to avoid doing it.
以避免这样做。
Why the sudden change of heart?
为何突然变心？
Tuan,
团,
I'm afraid if I don't,
恐怕如果我不这样做
You will leave me.
你会离开我的。
I'm the one
我就是被选择的那一位
who is afraid you will deny me.
谁怕你拒绝我。
Tuan.
团。
without you,
没有你，
I won't get the job.
我不会得到这份工作。
I like being a bailiff.
我喜欢当法警。
I like catching bad guys.
我喜欢抓坏人。
But sir,
但是先生，
do I need
我需要
against my conscience?
违背我的良心？
Sangeng.
Sangeng.
Conscience is such a thing.
良心就是这样的东西。
If you want to sell it,
如果你想卖掉它，
It won't sell for much.
卖不了多少钱。
But if you want to keep it,
但如果你想保留它
then it is expensive.
那么它很贵。
I don't think so
我不这么认为
You can pay the price.
你可以付出代价。
He is a good person.
他是一个好人。
I just know
我只知道
He is a very powerful person.
他是一个非常有权力的人。
A strong man cannot be a good man.
一个坚强的人 不可能是一个好人。
This powerful person even lost his life.
这个强者， 竟然还丢了性命。
The killer must be more powerful than him.
凶手的 实力一定比他更强。
Mother
母亲
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
I know.
我知道。
You will avenge your master.
你将为你的主人报仇。
I'm afraid.
我耽心。
mother,
母亲，
I am a bailiff.
我是一名法警。
In this world,
在这世上，
How can Malays be afraid of Malays?
马来人怎么会害怕马来人呢？
I've been blind for three years.
我已经失明三年了
At that time,
当时，
It seems
它似乎
It never dawns.
它永远不会黎明。
Always at night.
总是在晚上。
Darkness
黑暗
Always remember your father.
永远记住你的父亲。
He always tells us
他总是告诉我们
A guard is also an officer.
警卫也是军官。
So he is looking for a thief
所以他正在寻找小偷
While he was on patrol.
就在他巡逻的时候。
He never caught a thief.
他从来没有抓到过小偷。
He has put out several fires.
他已经扑灭了几场火灾。
But...
但...
Eventually,
最终，
He died saving people from fire.
他为救人们脱离火灾而牺牲。
My lord said he was a good man.
我的主人说他是一个好人。
Then,
然后，
The entire hallway was pitch black,
整个走廊一片漆黑，
And it was your father With his light that gave light,
那是你的父亲 用他的光照亮，
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
After his father died,
他父亲去世后，
You are my light.
你是我的光。
mother,
母亲，
Do not worry.
不用担心。
I will
我会
shining bright
闪闪发亮
Mr. Song.
宋先生。
Raise your hand.
举起你的手。
Any idea what this is?
知道这是什么吗？
These are teeth.
这些是牙齿。
What teeth?
什么牙齿？
I think it's a molar.
我认为这是一颗臼齿。
Do you know what is special?
你知道什么特别吗？
about this molar.
关于这颗臼齿。
Look carefully.
仔细地看。
I really don't know.
我真的不知道。
Molars usually have three roots.
臼齿通常有三个根。
This one has four.
这个有四个。
I will give it to you.
我会将它交给你。
Why?
为什么？
This tooth is rare.
这颗牙很少见。
You are lucky.
你很幸运。
Thank you, Mr. Song.
谢谢你，宋先生。
I will take my leave.
我要告辞了。
On that day, Captain Lang
那天，郎队长
go to Cuihua Tower, right?
去翠华楼吧？
I do not know.
我不知道。
Is Lin Siniang from that place
林四娘是那个地方的人吗
and your master's old lover?
还有你主人的旧情人？
I never heard of it.
我从来没有听说过。
This is very nice.
这非常好。
Sangeng.
Sangeng.
Save it for me.
给我保存一下。
Okey.
好的。
Where are you?
你在哪里？
Captain Yi is looking for you.
易队长正在找你。
I will go there.
我将会去那里。
Do not go.
不要去。
Why?
为什么？
Today, Captain Yi has sent all
今天，易队长已全部送出
from members on duty.
来自值班成员。
I was also given a task.
我也被分配了一个任务。
But I found something wrong
但我发现有些不对劲
and turned away.
然后转身走开。
I feel.
我觉得。
He will deal with you.
他会对付你的。
So, you have to hide first.
所以，你必须先躲起来。
I'll get them back.
我会把它们找回来。
At least wait until Jin comes back. Then we went to see him together.
至少要等Jin回来吧。 然后我们就一起去看他了。
I can't hide forever.
我不能永远隐藏。
It's just a matter of time
这只是时间问题
As long as I'm here.
只要我在这里。
All right, I'll come with you.
好吧，我跟你一起去。
I will go alone.
我一个人去。
Don't get involved.
不要参与其中。
Well, then be careful.
嗯，那就小心点吧。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Guard house.
警卫室。
It is the same way.
也是一样的。
Qu Sangeng,
Qu Sangeng,
Look at you now. You are in a mess.
看看你现在。你一团糟。
You don't look like an officer at all.
你看起来一点也不像军官。
Where did you go?
你去哪儿？
I was called by Mr. Song.
宋先生给我打电话。
Mr. Song?
宋先生？
Why did he do that?
他为什么那样做？
He gave me something.
他给了我一些东西。
This is...
这是...
It is a tooth.
它是一颗牙齿。
Molar teeth.
臼齿。
Molar teeth usually have three roots.
臼齿通常有三个牙根。
It has four roots.
它有四个根。
Why did Mr. Song give you teeth?
宋先生为什么要给你补牙？
He says there is no reason.
他说没有理由。
It rarely happens,
这种情况很少发生，
And I was lucky.
我很幸运。
Are you kidding me now?
你现在在开玩笑吗？
Who dares to make a joke about Mr. Song in Yemen?
也门谁敢拿宋先生开玩笑？
If you don't believe me, you can ask yourself.
如果你不相信我， 你可以问问你自己。
Let's not discuss it,
我们先不讨论这个问题
But your job.
但你的工作。
Since you are a bailiff,
既然你是法警，
Your task is to catch the thief.
你的任务是抓住小偷。
Case of Stolen Antique Jade Vase
古董玉瓶被盗案
from Mr. Cui's house.
来自崔先生家。
Still not resolved?
还没有解决吗？
It was dealt with together by me and my master.
这是我和我师父一起处理的。
Your master again?
又是你师父？
Baiklah, Qu Sangeng,
Baiklah, Qu Sangeng,
Do you plan to work with their name in the future.
您将来是否打算以他们的名字合作？
I will give you
我会给你
three days.
三天。
If you cannot complete it within three days,
如果三天内无法完成，
I will fire you.
我会解雇你。
What else?
还有什么？
No need.
不需要。
What?
什么？
Who
WHO
It was done by a tenant named Cui Shun.
这是一个名叫崔顺的佃户做的。
Tell me again.
再说一遍。
Mr. Cui likes antiques.
崔先生喜欢古董。
Cui Shun's task is to help him Find antiques everywhere.
崔顺的任务是帮他 到处寻找古董。
This vase was obtained illegally
这个花瓶是非法获得的
from grave robbers.
来自盗墓贼。
With all the antiques in the room,
房间里摆满了古董，
Only the Jade Vase is missing.
唯独玉瓶不见了。
Perhaps, the thief knows its origin and thinks
也许， 小偷知道它的来历并认为
Mr Cui will not report it.
崔先生不会报告此事。
But in Cui's house,
但在崔家，
Other than Cui Shun, No one knew his origin.
除了崔顺， 没有人知道他的来历。
And when We asked him,
当我们问他时，
He panicked and contradicted himself.
他惊慌失措，自相矛盾。
I will go to Cui's house to arrest him.
我这就去崔家抓捕他。
For tomorrow's seeds.
为了明天的种子。
Okay.
好的。
For this case,
对于这种情况，
I would hardly consider you passed.
我几乎不会认为你通过了。
Just that.
只是。
Raise your teeth.
抬起你的牙齿。
Do whatever you need to do.
做任何你需要做的事。
Wait.
等待。
What else do you need?
你还需要什么？
I didn't call you.
我没有打电话给你。
What is your name?
你叫什么名字？
Captain Yi,
Captain Yi,
Saya Gao Shicong.
Saya Gao Shicong.
Assistant bailiff?
助理法警？
Of.
的。
Show your badge.
出示您的徽章。
Today is your last day.
今天是你的最后一天。
You are fired.
你被开除了。
Fired?
被解雇？
Why?
为什么？
Do I need an excuse?
我需要借口吗？
Delete the bailiff's assistant?
删除法警助理？
Happy
快乐的
Isn't this just a job?
这不就是一份工作吗？
It's not a big deal.
没什么大不了的。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
You know my father is a butcher, right?
你知道我父亲是个屠夫，对吧？
I became an assistant bailiff
我成为一名助理法警
to avoid becoming a butcher like him.
以免成为像他一样的屠夫。
But now...
但现在...
Now what?
怎么办？
Now,
现在，
I am interested in slaughtering pigs.
我对杀猪很感兴趣。
Why?
为什么？
Every pig I will kill in the future
未来我要杀的每一头猪
Ya, ya.
是啊，是啊。
If my father had not died,
如果我父亲没有去世，
I think I will spend the night with him.
我想我会 和他一起过夜。
But your master is Captain Leng.
但你的师父是冷队长。
You are meant to be a bailiff.
你注定要成为一名法警。
Back in the day,
早些时候，
Yi was very afraid of Captain Leng.
易非常害怕冷队长。
But he took over
但他接手了
after the death of Captain Leng.
冷队长死后。
A group of mice.
一群老鼠。
They must die.
他们必须死。
Pig slaughter requires stability.
生猪屠宰需要稳定。
Cut it open for bleeding.
把它切开放血。
That's right.
这是正确的。
Then blow air into the hole,
然后将空气吹入孔中，
So it's easier on the skin.
所以对皮肤来说更容易。
That's right.
这是正确的。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
Stop hitting him.
别再打他了。
You dare to chase me.
你竟然敢追我。
I'm not after you.
我不是在追你。
I came to buy wine.
我是来买酒的。
Want to buy wine?
想买酒吗？
of all pubs,
在所有酒吧中，
Why do you have to come here?
你为什么一定要来这里？
Lovely, he really is
可爱，他确实是
misunderstanding.
误解。
You're a rat.
你是一只老鼠。
I will kill you today.
今天我就杀了你。
Good luck, don't.
祝你好运，不要。
Go away.
离开。
Open the way.
开路。
Sangeng.
Sangeng.
Don't you see a bailiff
你没看到法警吗
worked before?
以前工作过吗？
Awesome, this...
厉害了，这个...
Who are you?
你是谁？
A scholar.
一位学者。
Qian Mo.
Qian Mo.
What is the charge?
收费是多少？
Provoke trouble
惹事生非
resisting arrest.
拒捕。
Provoking trouble
招惹 拒捕麻烦。
There is a problem?
有一个问题？
Come with me.
跟我来。
You now look like a bailiff.
你现在看起来像个法警。
Tuan.
团。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
there is still a long way to go.
还有很长的路要走。
Tuan,
团,
Why are you really dead?
为什么你真的死了？
Are you in someone's way to riches
你是否妨碍了某人的致富之路
or
或者
Are you doing something unfair?
你是不是在做一些不公平的事情？
If it is the latter,
如果是后者的话，
Will you leave me as your master?
你愿意留下我做你的主人吗？
You are always my master.
你永远是我的主人。
But you're a good person.
但你是个好人。
You're a good bailiff, aren't you?
你是个好法警，不是吗？
Already out.
已经出来了。
I know this road well.
我很熟悉这条路。
Does not require light.
不需要光。
No.
不。
It must be lit.
它必须被点燃。
No need.
不需要。
Let me do it.
让我来做吧。
Let me...
让我...
No candles?
没有蜡烛吗？
Why don't you put one?
为什么不放一个呢？
Okay.
好的。
I know this road well.
我很熟悉这条路。
I plan to put candles
我打算放蜡烛
after turning that corner.
转过那个拐角后。
You know me?
你了解我？
YY-Your face is normal.
YY-你的脸很正常。
Look carefully.
仔细地看。
I'm in the Hunter Squad.
我是猎人小队的一员
I know your leader, Chen Shiba.
我认识你们的领导，陈十八。
Tell me the truth.
告诉我真相。
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
Okay.
好的。
II - I beg your pardon.
II - 请原谅。
Please don't tell my boss,
请不要告诉我的老板
Or I will lose my job.
否则我会失去工作。
Please have mercy.
请怜悯。
PP-Please.
PP-拜托。
Be thankful.
心存感激。
I beg.
我包
Do you trade candles for money?
你用蜡烛换钱吗？
II - I have many children.
II - 我有很多孩子。
We are poor.
我们很穷。
PP-Please.
PP-拜托。
Please let me go.
请放我走。
Please show mercy
请怜悯
And let me go.
然后让我走。
It is very dark tonight.
今晚天很黑。
without light,
没有光，
What if you travel?
如果你旅行怎么办？
I'm not the only one.
我不是唯一一个。
Everyone does this.
每个人都这样做。
I am used to it.
我习惯了。
Still no customers.
仍然没有顾客。
Wait until more people come.
等更多人来了。
Why should I wait until then?
我为什么要等到那时？
Are you not a singer?
你不是歌手吗？
Tuan,
团,
Let me fill it in.
让我填写一下。
Gui's.
贵的.
I went to Yemen for you.
我为了你去了也门。
They said you didn't go.
他们说你没去。
No,
不，
I'm not going today.
我今天不去。
I...
我...
Gui'er,
桂儿，
How could you come here as a young woman?
你怎么能 以一个年轻女子的身份来到这里？
If you are here
如果你在这里
as a bailiff?
作为法警？
Gui's.
贵的.
My hat.
我的帽子。
Come in.
进来。
are you drunk
你醉了吗
Wait here.
在这儿等着。
I will get my father's clothes for you.
我去给你拿我父亲的衣服。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
does it fit
合身吗
It's okay.
没关系。
Then just use it.
然后就用它吧。
My father didn't mind
我父亲并不介意
you wear his clothes
你穿他的衣服
Gui's
桂氏
I do not...
我不...
Are you facing any difficulties?
您面临任何困难吗？
Let my father help you.
让我父亲帮你吧。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
Do you still remember this basement?
你还记得这个地下室吗？
Certainly.
当然。
Don't we use to spend a lot of time here?
我们不是常常 在这里度过很多时间吗？
Do you remember this?
你记得这个吗？
Of.
的。
Ever since I can remember,
自从我有记忆以来，
This coffin is always here.
这口棺材一直都在这里。
I feel strange, thinking
我觉得奇怪，想着
Only parents will be provided first.
首先只提供父母。
My lord said it was uncertain
主人说这还不确定
When an accident may happen to a bailiff.
当法警 可能发生意外时。
This coffin
这口棺材
can not be used.
不能使用。
Why?
为什么？
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
Open the lid of this coffin.
打开这口棺材的盖子。
I think
我认为
10,000 languages.
10,000 种语言。
He didn't tell anyone,
他没有告诉任何人，
Not even my mother.
连我妈妈也不行。
My family is not rich
我的家庭并不富裕
But not poor.
但并不穷。
We have a farm outside the city.
我们在城外有一个农场。
And with his salary as bailiff,
加上他作为法警的薪水，
it is impossible to have this much money.
不可能有这么多钱。
Master has been a bailiff for many years.
师父当了多年的法警。
Everyone in this village respects him.
这个村子里的每个人都尊敬他。
He got a gift,
他得到了一份礼物，
And for years, he kept it.
多年来，他一直保留着它。
Ia...
伊阿...
I am not an officer,
我不是军官，
But I'm not that stupid.
但我没那么傻。
How many years will it take to save him this much?
到底要多少年才能 救他这么多？
Besides, he didn't save all this money.
更何况，这些钱他也不是全存的。
Not by saving?
不是靠储蓄吗？
These silver bars are all stamped.
这些银条上都刻有印记。
All these are collected in one batch.
所有这些都收集在一批中。
Gui's
桂氏
What do you suspect?
你怀疑什么？
People die for money.
人们为钱而死。
in Yemen,
在也门，
No one is clean.
没有人是干净的。
But Sir
但是先生
not like them.
不喜欢他们。
I don't care whether he is clean or dirty.
我不在乎他是干净还是肮脏。
No matter what, he is my father.
不管怎样，他都是我的父亲。
He may have been responsible
他可能有责任
for the big wrong case.
对于大错案。
There's something else.
还有别的事。
It was just after 1am.
当时是凌晨 1 点刚过。
The drum just sounded.
鼓声刚刚响起。
The East Garden of the Lu House caught fire.
卢府东花园 失火。
It is the west wind.
这是西风。
Our West Park is affected.
我们的西园受到了影响。
We have the help of our neighbors,
我们有邻居的帮助，
So it's not bad.
所以这还不错。
Niu Lubao.
Niu Lubao.
7 September, 1589.
1589 年 9 月 7 日。
1589?
1589？
This is all from 20 years ago.
这都是20年前的事了。
They are the testimony of the neighbors after the fire.
这是火灾发生后邻居们的证词。
They are almost the same,
他们几乎是一样的，
except His guidance.
除了他的指导。
Several other areas have been mentioned.
还提到了其他几个领域。
Apparently the Lu Residence is very big.
看来陆府 很大。
Is the house on fire on all sides at the same time?
房子 四面八方同时着火吗？
Recipe?
食谱？
They are also from 20 years ago.
他们也是20年前的。
Given to two men,
送给两个男人，
Chen Wang
Chen Wang
dan Lu Yuanbao.
dan Lu Yuanbao.
The doctor was Cheng Yizhi.
医生就是程亦之。
That genius doctor?
那个神医？
I think so.
我想是这样。
Teachers are meticulous always planning ahead.
老师们总是一丝不苟地 提前计划。
I'm afraid this is
恐怕这是
life saving chip.
救生芯片。
Are you saying this is proof?
你说这就是证据？
10,000 languages.
10,000 种语言。
Who can come with so much silver He is not an ordinary person.
谁能带着这么多银子来， 他可不是一般人。
Did my father keep the evidence
我父亲有保留证据吗
to hold someone?
抱着某人？
So,
所以，
Can it be
是真的吗
That my father was killed for the sake of those behind him.
我的父亲是 为了他身后的人而被杀的。
Now there is no way to know.
现在没有办法知道。
Oh, right, Sangeng,
哦，对了，三更，
You just mentioned the date.
你刚才提到了日期。
What do you think?
你怎么认为？
It is
这是
My Father's Death Anniversary Date
我父亲的忌日
Gui's
桂氏
Without my lord,
没有我的主，
I would not be who I am today.
我不会是今天的我。
Whether he is good
无论他好不好
or bad,
还是不好，
He is
他是
Always my lord.
永远是我的主。
mother,
母亲，
I have a question.
我有个问题。
Go away.
离开。
Where is the fire that my father put out?
我父亲扑灭的火在哪里？
It is on Hehe Lane near Tieshizi Road.
位于 铁石子路附近的和合巷。
A newcomer named Lu.
一个叫陆的新人。
His entire family died.
他的全家都死了。
Why are you suddenly asking about it?
你怎么突然问这个？
Teacher still remains Evidences from the fire.
老师还留下 火灾的证据。
Is the fire a big event
火灾是大事件吗
to your master?
给你的主人？
He never mentioned it to me.
他从来没有向我提起过这件事。
And he still sticks to the information given,
他仍然坚持所提供的信息，
Therefore, it was not normal for him.
因此，这对他来说是不正常的。
Not surprising.
不奇怪。
Mother
母亲
No wonder what?
难怪什么？
I never heard your father mention it before.
我以前从未听你父亲提起过这件事。
He has any interaction with your master.
他和你的主人有任何互动 。
After your father died,
你父亲去世后，
He came several times.
他来过几次。
I thought at first
我一开始以为
He only went through the motions because he was in the hunting squad.
他只是走走过场， 因为他是狩猎队的一员。
Unexpectedly,
不料，
He gave me a lot of money
他给了我很多钱
and tell me
然后告诉我
He is your father's best friend.
他是你父亲最好的朋友。
Niu Lubao.
Niu Lubao.
That is me.
那是我。
Do you remember the Lu Residence Fire 20 years ago?
你还记得 20年前的卢宅火灾吗？
Yes I know.
是的，我知道。
I remember.
我记得。
- Yes. How could I not remember?
- 是的。我怎么会不记得呢？
The Lu family is rich.
卢家很有钱。
It scared me so bad
这让我害怕极了
that my breasts are empty.
我的乳房是空的。
My second child was raised on soy milk.
我的第二个孩子是喝豆浆长大的。
What?
什么？
A big fire at the Lu Residence 20 years ago!
20年前陆家大火！
Fire?
火？
Where is it?
它在哪里？
That night, I couldn't sleep.
那天晚上，我无法入睡。
I am angry with my wife.
我对我的妻子很生气。
I don't remember why.
我不记得为什么。
He's definitely tempting.
他绝对很有诱惑力。
My wife is a chat box.
我的妻子是一个聊天盒子。
Tuan,
团,
Are you married?
你结婚了吗？
I told you.
我告诉你了。
Better to marry a dumb person.
还不如嫁个傻子。
When did the fire start?
火灾是什么时候开始的？
Okay.
好的。
It is either 11pm or 1am.
现在是晚上 11 点或凌晨 1 点。
I just heard
我刚听说
Drum.
鼓。
Then suddenly...
然后突然间...
Guess what?
你猜怎么了？
What?
什么？
Fireballs fell from the sky.
火球从天而降。
This ball of fire floats
这团火球飘浮在空中
and float
并漂浮
on the roof of Lu's house.
卢家的屋顶上。
It started rolling.
它开始滚动。
In an instant,
顷刻，
The house turned into a sea of ​​fire.
房子变成了一片火海。
I have your testimony from 20 years ago
我有你20年前的见证
Which doesn't mention any fireballs.
其中没有提到任何火球。
I'm busy with the fire.
我正忙着救火呢。
until dawn that night,
直到那天晚上天亮，
Maybe I forgot to mention it
也许我忘了提及
in confusion.
混乱中。
I'm not the only one.
我不是唯一一个。
All our neighbors saw it.
我们所有的邻居都看到了。
We often sit together and drink.
我们经常坐在一起喝酒。
When someone mentions a fireball,
当有人提到火球时
Everyone said they saw it.
大家都说看到了。
(Yue Fortune Teller) A very hot fire,
(乐算命先生) 火很热，
stay until late the next morning.
待到第二天早上很晚。
Until everything is burned to ashes.
直到一切都被烧成灰烬。
My family did not fall at that time.
我的家人当时并没有倒下。
I look poor now.
我现在看起来很穷。
My family was rich at that time,
那时我家很有钱，
and I am still a student in the district school.
我还是 区学校的学生。
I am a classmate of the Young Lord of the Lu Family.
我是陆家少爷的同学。
Fortunately, I met my master.
幸运的是，我遇到了我的师父。
who taught me about divination, geomancy,
谁教我占卜、风水、
Face reading skills and luck.
读脸技巧和运气。
Sir, you have an amazing face.
先生，您有一张令人惊叹的脸。
Do you want your future predicted?
你想预测你的未来吗？
No.
不。
This is your testimony from 20 years ago
这是你20年前的见证
Fire at Lu's house.
卢家失火。
Tuan,
团,
I can't read.
我无法阅读。
There are rumors of a fire.
有传言称发生火灾。
What's that?
那是什么？
It is said
据说
Which is the master of the family
哪个是家里的主人
do something cruel.
做一些残忍的事情。
A passing Taoist accidentally found out about
路过的道士 无意中发现
and decided to do justice.
并决定伸张正义。
Taoism used the Five Thunder Technique
道教使用 五雷法
To summon Thunder to cover the master's bedroom,
召唤雷霆 笼罩主人的卧室，
That's a big fire.
那是一场大火。
Speaking of which,
说到这，
There are rumors.
有传言。
What's the rumor?
谣言是什么？
The teacher is crazy.
老师疯了。
The fire was lit by him.
火是他点燃的。
Before that,
在那之前，
He killed his brother.
他杀了他的兄弟。
Are there any survivors from the Lu family?
陆家还有幸存者吗？
No.
不。
All servers are dead.
所有服务器都死了。
I don't think there is anyone left in the Lu family.
我想陆家已经没有人了。
Tuan,
团,
who
WHO
has been closed by Yemen.
也门已关闭。
You can check it out.
你可以检查一下。
please
请
Your mother's illness is caused by
你母亲的病是由
For the sake of the beyond-limits distress that causes the lungs,
为了引起肺部的过度痛苦，
heart and liver damage.
心脏和肝脏受损。
So it must take time.
所以这必须需要时间。
Let him take these three doses first.
让他先服下这三剂。
Then watch him.
然后看着他。
Of.
的。
Dr. Cheng.
Dr. Cheng.
This...
这...
He was my father's apprentice.
他是我父亲的徒弟。
My name is Qu Sangeng.
我叫曲三庚。
I just want to see you.
我只是想看看你。
What for?
做什么的？
I have several prescriptions.
我有几个处方。
I want you to check them out.
我想让你检查一下。
This is the recipe I made.
这是我做的食谱。
According to time,
按照时间来看，
They are from 20 years ago.
他们是20年前的。
So you're sure you made this?
所以你确定这是你做的吗？
Yes its me.
是的，是我。
So do you remember
那么你还记得吗
both patients.
两位患者。
Lu Yuanbao used to be a rich employee.
陆元宝曾经是一个有钱的员工。
This is not for serious illnesses.
这不适用于严重疾病。
Only for throbbing and shortness of breath.
仅表现为心悸 和呼吸急促。
especially nutrients.
尤其是营养素。
But Chen Wang.
但陈旺。
I don't remember him.
我不记得他了。
But this prescription
但这个处方
Aim for the fire of the heart.
瞄准心中的火焰。
Not a serious illness.
不是严重的疾病。
20 years ago, Lu Residence There was a big fire.
20年前，卢宅 发生了一场大火。
Do you know about it?
你知道吗？
It seems so.
看来是这样。
Where did you get it
你在哪里得到它
Old recipe?
老食谱？
I just happened to see them
我只是碰巧看到他们
in the file folder in Yamen when looking at other things.
看其他东西的时候在衙门的文件夹里。
I want to know.
我想知道。
Very strange.
很奇怪。
I have been to Yemen to testify many times.
我多次前往也门作证。
If the information is evidence,
如果信息是证据，
So my testimony must be there.
所以我的见证一定在那里。
Did you find my testimony in the documents?
你在文件中找到我的证词了吗？
No.
不。
But it's been 20 years.
但已经过去20年了。
It is possible Some case documents are missing.
某些案件文件可能 丢失。
I really don't remember
我真的不记得了
both patients.
两位患者。
After all, that was 20 years ago.
毕竟那是20年前的事了。
I must have treated
我一定已经治疗过
Many patients at that time.
当时病人很多。
But...
但...
In fact, these letters are mine.
事实上，这些信是我的。
and they are right.
他们是对的。
I...
我...
I wondered
我想知道
Why do you want to discuss this old thing?
为什么要讨论这个老东西呢？
Please don't be offended.
请不要生气。
This is not an urgent matter.
这不是一个紧急的事情。
I just want to ask you
我只想问你
If you remember both patients.
如果你还记得 这两个病人的话。
This is not about prescription.
这与处方无关。
If that happens,
如果发生这种情况，
I will take my leave.
我要告辞了。
I have another patient.
我还有另一个病人。
Thank You.
谢谢。
Take your time with medications.
花点时间服用药物。
Dr. Cheng didn't tell the truth.
程医生没有说实话。
He must know something.
他一定知道一些事情。
What does he know?
他知道什么？
Wang Rui,
Wang Rui,
This pear is for mom.
这个梨是给妈妈的。
There are too many.
太多了。
He can't eat it all.
他不能全部吃完。
He should be the first to eat.
他应该是第一个吃的。
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
I'll take one.
我要一份。
Rui,
芮，
How much do you eat?
你吃多少？
I just ate one.
我刚吃了一个。
No.
不。
I washed five.
我洗了五个。
But now there are only three.
但现在只剩下三个了。
You must have eaten two.
你肯定吃了两个
Nope. I only ate one.
没有。我只吃了一个。
Then the missing?
那么失踪的呢？
Certainly Sangeng.
当然是三更。
I haven't been in the room yet.
我还没进过房间呢
You are the one who eats it.
你就是那个吃它的人。
Good for you, Leng Rui.
干得好，冷锐。
Then it must be Dr. Cheng.
那一定是程医生了。
Balderdash!
梦呓！
Sangeng!
Sangeng!
Is Sangeng here?
三更在吗？
Is he here?
他在这里吗？
Sangeng!
Sangeng!
Sangeng,
Sangeng,
Wulei School.
武磊学校.
Come with me.
跟我来。
The students came this morning.
今天早上学生们来了。
and found the door locked.
并发现门锁着。
They knocked but no one answered.
他们敲了敲门，但没有人应门。
Later,
之后，
My uncle came to cook but also failed.
舅舅来做饭却没成功。
So, they called me.
所以，他们打电话给我。
I climb on top of the wall,
我爬上墙顶，
and then I saw it.
然后我看到了。
It's still not sure He's Mr. Wang, right?
现在还不能确定 他就是王先生吧？
I'm sure.
我敢肯定。
These shoes
这些鞋子
made by my mother.
我妈妈做的。
This is a seal.
这是一个印章。
My uncle loves Calligraphy and seal carving.
我叔叔喜欢 书法和篆刻。
He never used . and . on his students.
他从来没有用过 。和 。在他的学生身上。
And when they fast,
当他们禁食时，
He uses wood or bamboo.
他使用木头或竹子。
This copper ferule
这个铜箍
used to press books.
用来压书的。
Young people.
年轻人。
Dressed in clothes
穿着衣服
at the end of spring.
春天结束时。
Malay
马来语
and young people.
和年轻人。
bathing in the river Yi,
沐浴伊河，
And the wind on the altar.
还有祭坛上的风。
Home with songs
有歌声的家
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
At the end of spring,
春天结束时，
I wear newly made clothes.
我穿着新做的衣服。
Some adults and children
一些成人和儿童
Take a dip in the Yi River
畅游伊河
And We rejoice with the wind on the high altar,
我们因高坛上的风而欢欣鼓舞，
After that,
在那之后，
We returned home
我们回到家
Sing.
唱歌。
Shovel.
铲。
Go get a shovel.
去拿把铲子。
(No penalty)
（没有惩罚）
??? In the middle of the bones, Next to the knife ???
??? 在骨头中间， 刀旁边？？？
??? Something sweet and sticky???
??? 又甜又粘的东西？？？
??? Biting through old times ???
??? 穿越旧时光？？？
??? Some cry and some sleep???
??? 有的哭有的睡？？？
??? A great offer Served as a sacrifice ???
??? 一个伟大的提议 作为牺牲？？？
??? And there are innocent mountains, with flies flying around ???
??? 还有无辜的山， 苍蝇飞来飞去？？？
??? Old way far away Prosperous city ???
??? 老路遥远 繁华都市？？？
??? Wildfires never stop, withering and growing???
??? 野火永不停歇， 枯萎又壮大？？？
??? Several lines of smoke curled up???
??? 几道烟雾袅袅升起？？？
??? You make a request???
??? 你提出要求？？？
??? Empty promises and sad stories ???
??? 空洞的承诺和悲伤的故事？？？
??? Disappear without a trace ???
??? 消失得无影无踪？？？
??? A great offer Served as a sacrifice ???
??? 一个伟大的提议 作为牺牲？？？
??? And there are innocent mountains, with flies flying around ???
??? 还有无辜的山， 苍蝇飞来飞去？？？
??? Old way far away Prosperous city ???
??? 老路遥远 繁华都市？？？
??? Wildfires never stop, withering and growing???
??? 野火永不停歇， 枯萎又壮大？？？